<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Researches on Home</title><link>https://example.org/research/</link><description>Recent content in Researches on Home</description><generator>Hugo 0.64.0 -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>skojaku@iu.edu (Sadamori Kojaku)</managingEditor><webMaster>skojaku@iu.edu (Sadamori Kojaku)</webMaster><copyright>Sadamori Kojaku — All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.org/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Residual2Vec - Debiasing graph embedding with random graphs</title><link>https://example.org/research/residual2vec/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate><author>skojaku@iu.edu (Sadamori Kojaku)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">https://example.org/research/residual2vec/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>S. Kojaku, J. Yoon, I. Constantino, Y.-Y. Ahn. NeurIPS (2021)&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[Paper (in press)], [&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.07654">Preprint&lt;/a>], [&lt;a href="https://github.com/skojaku/residual2vec">Code&lt;/a>], [&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1cqk9RtUw5Qlmz5gvpIKtF12b9NJiFgV4/view?usp=sharing">Slide&lt;/a>] [&lt;a href="https://observablehq.com/@skojaku/visualizing-journal-embeddings">Interactive Vis.&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Your friends have more friends than you do&amp;rdquo; is a mathematical necessity known as &lt;em>the friendship paradox&lt;/em>. Beyond an interesting piece of trivia, it has substantial importance in graph embeddings: many graph embeddings learn the graph structure by following the &amp;lsquo;friendship ties&amp;rsquo; (or edges), which preferentially leads itself to high-degree nodes. How does this bias toward high-degree nodes impact on the generated embedding? Here, we find an overlooked built-in debiasing feature of word2vec that happens to negate the bias due to the friendship paradox. We demonstrate that this overlooked debiasing feature can be used to negate other types of bias, and enables us to control the bias in graph embeddings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="padding:56.25% 0 0 0;position:relative;">&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/635866503?h=2aa318f56b&amp;amp;badge=0&amp;amp;autopause=0&amp;amp;player_id=0&amp;amp;app_id=58479" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" title="Residual2Vec: Debiasing graph embedding with random graphs">&lt;/iframe>&lt;/div>&lt;script src="https://player.vimeo.com/api/player.js">&lt;/script></description></item><item><title>Citation cartels</title><link>https://example.org/research/citation-cartels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate><author>skojaku@iu.edu (Sadamori Kojaku)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">https://example.org/research/citation-cartels/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sadamori Kojaku&lt;/strong>, Giacomo Livan, and Naoki Masuda. Detecting anomalous citation groups in journal networks. Scientific Reports, 11, 1-11 (2021).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-93572-3">[Paper]&lt;/a> [&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2009.09097">Preprint&lt;/a>], [&lt;a href="https://github.com/skojaku/cidre">Code&lt;/a>], [&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/12QkfRUMWFzxSPq2tC53DQ9Ek4RYuxJEx/view?usp=sharing">Slide&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A fundamental principle in all areas of science is encapsulated by what is known as Kelvin&amp;rsquo;s maxim: &amp;ldquo;To measure is to know,&amp;rdquo; so-named for the father of Physics, William Thomson, Lord Kelvin. Although simple to state for physical experiments, measuring people is notoriously difficult, in part because people change actions in response to measurement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Scientists are measured in many ways, e.g., # of publications, citations, h-index, and to name a few. These indicators appear to be hard, sound neutral and give an air of objectivity, and are considered as a proxy for ``scientific excellence&amp;rsquo;'. These indicators are indispensable for research assessment for grants and tenure, creating an ever-increasing pressure to maintain high-performance indicators. As such, some scientists game the system by artificially boosting citations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Self-citations are a simple and famous practice to increase citations, although self-citations can be easily detected. A less detectable form of citation malpractice is &lt;em>citation cartel&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A citation cartel is a group of scientists who informally agree to cite with each other. Because it involves multiple scientists, identifying citation cartels is notoriously challenging, and little is known about this phenomenon itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here, we put forward an algorithm, CIDRE, to find anomalous citation groups in citation networks. With CIDRE, we systematically explore the anomalous citation behavior of journals. CIDRE detected more than half of known groups of journals suspended from Journal Citation Reports along with numerous new journal groups with anomalous citation patterns.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="padding:62.5% 0 0 0;position:relative;">&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/582302595?badge=0&amp;amp;autopause=0&amp;amp;player_id=0&amp;amp;app_id=58479&amp;amp;h=8e5a0ba380" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" title="Detecting anomalous citation groups in journal networks">&lt;/iframe>&lt;/div>&lt;script src="https://player.vimeo.com/api/player.js">&lt;/script></description></item><item><title>Contact tracing</title><link>https://example.org/research/contact-tracing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate><author>skojaku@iu.edu (Sadamori Kojaku)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">https://example.org/research/contact-tracing/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sadamori Kojaku&lt;/strong>, Laurent Hébert-Dufresne, Enys Mones, Sune Lehmann, Yong-Yeol Ahn. The effectiveness of backward contact tracing in networks. Nature Physics (2021).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41567-021-01187-2">Paper&lt;/a>], [&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2005.02362">Preprint&lt;/a>], [ &lt;a href="https://github.com/yy/backward-contact-tracing">Code&lt;/a> ]&lt;a name="scola-ref">&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Core-periphery structure of networks</title><link>https://example.org/research/core-periphery-structure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate><author>skojaku@iu.edu (Sadamori Kojaku)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">https://example.org/research/core-periphery-structure/</guid><description>&lt;p>*Sadamori Kojaku, Naoki Masuda. New Journal of Physics, 20, 043012 (2018)*&lt;br>
&lt;em>Sadamori Kojaku, Naoki Masuda. Physical Revew E, 96, 052313 (2017)&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Core-periphery structure is a mesoscale structure of networks, where a core is a group of densely interconnected nodes, and a periphery is a group of sparsely interconnected nodes.
Core-periphery structure has been found in various empirical networks such as social networks, biological networks and transportation networks [1, 2].
Many studies have assumed that networks consist of one core and one periphery.
However, networks may contain multiple core-periphery pairs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We developed an algorithm to find multiple core-periphery pairs in networks [3].
In the political blog network [4] shown in Fig. 1, the algorithm found two core-periphery pairs, each of which consists of the blogs sharing the same political agenda.
We applied this algorithm or its variant to an inter-bank trade network [5], a maritime transportation network [6] and a short-text classification task [7].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also showed that heterogeneous degree distributions alone explain single core-periphery structure [8]. In other words, when one says that a network is composed of a single core and a single periphery, hubs (i.e. nodes with large degrees, or the number of edges) are core nodes and nodes with small degrees are peripheral nodes. We proved that a core-periphery structure that is not merely explained by heterogeneous degree distributions necessarily involves at least three blocks of nodes. An example is a combination of a single core, a single periphery and a community, which yields three blocks. Another example is two core-periphery pairs, which yields four blocks in total. Based on this result, we extended our first algorithm [7] to find multiple core-periphery pairs in networks that are not merely explained by heterogeneous degree distributions [8].
The extended algorithm allows one to find small-degree core nodes and large-degree peripheral nodes.&lt;/p>
&lt;div align="center">
&lt;img src="https://example.org/docs/core-periphery/poliblog.png" title="Core-periphery structure">
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Figure&lt;/strong>: Two core-periphery pairs in the political blog network detected by our algorithm.
The filled or open circles indicate core nodes or peripheral nodes, respectively.
The colour of each circle indicates the core-periphery pair to which the node belongs.
The open circles with a grey border indicate nodes that do not belong to any core-periphery pair.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="a-namecprefareferences">&lt;a name="cpref">&lt;/a>References&lt;/h5>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>P. Csermely, A. London, L.-Y. Wu, and B. Uzzi, Journal of Complex Networks, 1, 93 (2013) [&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/comnet/cnt016">link&lt;/a>]&lt;/li>
&lt;li>M. P. Rombach, M. A. Porter, J. H. Fowler, P. J. Mucha, `SIAM Review, 59, 619-646 (2017) [&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1137/17M1130046">link&lt;/a>]&lt;/li>
&lt;li>S. Kojaku and N. Masuda, Physical Review E, 96, 052313 (2017) [&lt;a href="//doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevE.96.052313">link&lt;/a>]&lt;/li>
&lt;li>L. A. Adamic and N. Glance, in Proceedings of the 3rd International Workshop on Link Discovery, 36–43 (ACM, New York, USA, 2005) [&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1145/1134271.1134277">link&lt;/a>]&lt;/li>
&lt;li>S. Kojaku, G. Cimini, G. Caldarelli, N. Masuda, Journal of Network Theory in Finance, 4, 33-51 (2018) [&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.21314/JNTF.2018.044">link&lt;/a>]&lt;/li>
&lt;li>X. Cui, S. Kojaku, N. Masuda, and D. Bollegala, in Proceedings of the 7th Joint Conference on Lexical and Computational Semantics, 225-264 (ACL, New Orleans, USA, 2018) [&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.18653/v1/S18-2030">link&lt;/a>]&lt;/li>
&lt;li>S. Kojaku, M. Xu, H. Xia, N. Masuda, `Preprint arXiv:1808.04549 (2018) [&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1808.04549">link&lt;/a>]&lt;/li>
&lt;li>S. Kojaku and N. Masuda, `New Journal of Physics 20, 043012 (2018) [&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1088/1367-2630/aab547">link&lt;/a>]&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Constructing networks from correlation matrices</title><link>https://example.org/research/correlation-matrix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate><author>skojaku@iu.edu (Sadamori Kojaku)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">https://example.org/research/correlation-matrix/</guid><description>&lt;p>*S. Kojaku and N. Masuda. Proceedings of the Royal Society A, 475, 2231 (2019)*&lt;br>
&lt;em>Naoki Masuda, Sadamori Kojaku, Yukie Sano. Physical Review E, 98, 012312 (2018)&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many networks of scientific interest have been constructed from correlation matrices.
Examples include protein interaction networks, gene co-expression networks, functional brain networks, climate networks and asset graphs.
In correlation networks, the edges indicate nontrivial correlations between the features of the nodes.
A widely accepted approach for constructing networks from correlation matrices is the thresholding; one places an edge between two nodes if the correlation is larger than a threshold.
However, the thresholding may induce spurious edges in the generated networks because a large correlation may be induced by a factor irrelevant to the node pair such as a global trend and pseudo correlations.
An example is a large correlation between ice cream sale and murder rate; people buy more ice cream and interact with more people when it is hotter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We developed an algorithm for constructing networks from correlation matrices, which we refer to as &lt;a href="https://scola.readthedocs.io/en/latest/">Scola&lt;/a>.
A key feature of the algorithm is to use the null models for correlation matrices, based on which we decide whether to place edges between nodes or not.
In other words, we place edges between nodes whose correlations are &lt;em>unexpected&lt;/em> for the null models.
Users can run the algorithm with a null model of interest or let the algorithm to choose statistically the best null model among candidate null models.
For three economic data, the algorithm produces statistically better networks and more accurately predicts country-level product export volumes.&lt;/p>
&lt;div align="center">
&lt;img style="width:100%;max-width:800px;padding:5px" src="https://example.org/docs/threshold-networks/adj.png" title="Correlation networks">
&lt;/div>
&lt;br>
**Figure**:
Sample correlation matrices and networks for the product space data.
The solid lines inside the matrices indicate the boundary between year *t* (first half) and year *t*+10 (second half).
The node colour indicates the product type.
The value of the PRODY index averaged over the nodes in the same type is shown in the parentheses.</description></item></channel></rss>